Finding Aid for the Alvin Irving Levin Music Manuscripts PASC-M.0179
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alvin Irving Levin music manuscripts
1950-1997
UCLA Library Special Collections
Levin, Alvin Irving
PASC-M.0179
6.5 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
This collection consists of manuscript music scores and photocopies of compositions of Alvin Irving Levin
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Alvin Irving Levin; gift; 1999.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942350263606533
Biography
Levin graduated Ed.D. from UCLA in 1968; studied composition privately with Roy Harris for three years; served on Psychology faculty at Californian State University, Northridge; local performances have included Song of the Earth (1950), Venu Te Deum (1955), Confirmation Cantata (1959), Symphony for Strings (1984), and Hymn to the United Nations (1991).
Scope and Content
Manuscript music scores and photocopies of compositions of Alvin Irving Levin. Includes dramatic works, choral works, symphonic music, and chamber music.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Dramatic works
Choral works
Symphonic music
Chamber music and songs.
Composers -- Archives.; Music -- Manuscripts.; Levin, Alvin Irving, 1921- --Archives.
- Dramatic Works
  - My Ivory Tower
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 1. Manuscript full score, pencil masters. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 2. Manuscript full score, pencil masters. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - My Ivory Tower. Cantata: Song of Praise. Manuscript full score, pencil masters. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 3, Part 1. Manuscript full score, pencil masters. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 3, Part 2. Manuscript full score, pencil masters. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 1. Full score, photocopy of ms. masters. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      My Ivory Tower, a Modern Greek Epic Drama in Three Acts, for Narrator, Orchestra and Chorus (1995-1998). Full score, spiral bound, with introductory essay ("General Comments and Program Notes"). Subtitle also given as "a Multimedia Extravaganza in Three Acts". Subtitle of Act Two: Bacchanalian Orgy. Also: Cantata: Song of Praise, for Chorus, Organ and Orchestra, to be performed between Acts Two and Three. 6 spiral bound volumes.
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 2, Part 1. Full score, photocopy of ms. masters. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 2, Part 2. Full score, photocopy of ms. masters. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - My Ivory Tower. Cantata: Song of Praise. Full score, photocopy of ms. masters. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 3, Part 1. Full score, photocopy of ms. masters. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 3, Part 2. Full score, photocopy of ms. masters. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - My Ivory Tower. Sketches. Ms., pencil. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - My Ivory Tower. Part 1. Sketches. Ms., pencil. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - My Ivory Tower. Ballet, Part 2. Sketches. Ms., pencil. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 3, Part 1. Sketches. Ms., pencil. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - My Ivory Tower. Act 3, Part 2. Sketches. Ms., pencil. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - My Ivory Tower. Song of Praise. Sketches. Ms., pencil. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - My Ivory Tower (published text). By Alvin Irving Levin. Los Angeles: House-Warven, 1950. (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Publisher's edition. Copy no. 997 of 1000.
  - Happy Land
    - Happy Land (Musical). Full score. Photocopy of ms., 2 spiral bound volumes. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Happy Land. Piano vocal score. Ms., pencil. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - A Tale of Two Planets
    - A Tale of Two Planets (Musical). Act One, Part 1. Photocopy of ms. full score. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - A Tale of Two Planets. Act One, Part 2. Photocopy of ms. full score. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - A Tale of Two Planets. Act Two, Part 1. Photocopy of ms. full score. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - A Tale of Two Planets. Act Two, Part 2. Photocopy of ms. full score. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Choral Works
  - The Song of Hiawatha
    - The Song of Hiawatha (1993-1994). Photocopy of ms., spiral bound. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      "Symphonic Fantasy Ballet in Five Movements for Orchestra and Chorus."
    - The Song of Hiawatha (1993-94), symphonic fantasy ballet in five movements. Full score. Ms., pencil. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      For orchestra and chorus.
  - Beat! Beat! Drums!
    - Beat! Beat! Drums! Tone Poem for male chorus and brass (1984). Full score, ink, spiral bound. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Beat! Beat! Drums! (Drum Taps, text by Walt Whitman). Full score. Ms., pencil. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hymn to the United Nations
    - Hymn to the United Nations (1991). Full score. Ms., pencil. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      For chorus and orchestra.
    - Hymn to the United Nations (1991). Full score. Photocopy of the above, spiral bound. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Confirmation Cantata
    - Confirmation Cantata (1959). Ms., pencil. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Symphonic Music
  - Introspection
    - Introspection, for Symphony Orchestra (1997). Ms. full score, pencil masters. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Introspection, for Symphony Orchestra (1997). Spiral bound photocopy of the above. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Introspection, for Symphony Orchestra (1997). Ms. short score (sketches), pencil. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Violin Concerto
    - Concerto in A Minor, for Violin and Orchestra (1997). Ms. full score, pencil masters. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Concerto in A Minor, for Violin and Orchestra (1997). Spiral bound photocopy of the above. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      "To Itzhak Perlman."
    - Concerto in A Minor, for Violin and Orchestra (1997). Final sketches. Ms., pencil. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Song of the Earth
    - Song of the Earth: a psychological tone poem. Full score, ink, bound. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Song of the Earth, a psychological tone poem (1950). Short score. Ms., pencil. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - North Hollywood: Metamorphosis
    - North Hollywood: Metamorphosis; a symphonic suite for orchestra (1996). Photocopy of ms., spiral bound. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - North Hollywood: Metamorphosis; a symphonic suite for orchestra (1996). Draft of full score, pencil. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Symphony for Strings
    - Symphony for Strings (1965). Sketches. Ms., pencil. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Symphony for Strings (1965). Full score. Ozalid, spiral bound. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Chamber Music and Songs
  - We are not alone. Music, research, files, clippings. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Venu Te Deum, for violin and piano (1951). Score and part. Ms., ink. (Box 13, Folder 2)